Blair B. Betts 927 Berwick Valley Lane Cary, NC 27513 919-434-1853 blairbetts25@gmail.com

Objective:

As a former college athlete and coach, I have the drive and the passion to be the ultimate team player. Following my college coaching experience, I have decided to take my drive and passion to the tech world. I am currently expanding my degree in communications, experience with scoring programs and statistics into being a full stack developer. As a result of my experience in college athletics I know what it means to set goals, work to achieve those goals, and complete them. In addition, I have gathered the tools necessary to help encourage and motivate others to reach those goals so that the whole team can soar to new heights. I look forward to using my skills, passion and drive to strive for greatness into the tech world.

Experience:

Student in the UNC-Boot Camp for Full Stack Developers

1/2019-7/2019

- Learning the basics to become a full stack developer
- Content that will be learned in the course: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, MySQL, React, MongoDB, BootStrap, Express.JS, Git, C#, ASP.Net, Heroku

Evo-Shield Canes Baseball

9/2018-11/2019

- Head Coach for the 18u Canes Central Team
- Helped develop high school players who were searching to play at the collegiate level

UNC Greensboro Assistant Coach: Outfield Coach/Director of Operations

8/2017-6/2018

- In charge of all away travel arrangements including food, hotel, scheduling, and budget
- Coached outfield players to improve ball tracking and arm strength
- Organized and directed UNCG baseball camps
- Served as UNCG representative for recruiting evaluation at other school and organizations camps
- Designed season schedule stadium display poster
- Field maintenance, improvements and preparation

Louisburg College: Assistant Coach- Pitching/Outfield Coach 5/2017

6/2015-

- Assistant coach on new coaching staff that doubled team wins within two seasons
- Created overall pitching & throwing program
- Coached outfield players to improve ball tracking and arm strength
- Extensive recruiting along the southeastern coast to evaluate and attract top talent high school players

- Field maintenance, improvements and preparation
- Organized and implemented game day schedule
- Ran merchandising and concession stand operations
- Created design for alumni plaques, world series plaques, and official team gear
- Using IScore gathered game statistics and entered for the NJCAA official website
- Assisted in team social media postings including upcoming events, live action shots, and scoring updates

Holly Springs Salamander: Assistant Coach

5/2015-6/2015

North Carolina Special Olympics- Wake County: Assistant Coach

2009-

Present

Certified Special Olympics softball coach

Trained special needs athletes about proper playing techniques, improving softball skills, and good sportsmanship

Baseball Playing Experience:

NCAA Division 1 Pitcher

UNC Greensboro 2011-2015

Led UNCG in appearances for the 2014 and 2015 season

Indiana University 2010-2011

Additional Playing Experience

Peninsula Pilots, Coastal Plains League Summer 2013,2014

Coastal Plain League Champions 2013 & 2014 Led the team in appearances in 2013, 3rd in 2014

Myrtle Beach Summer LeagueSummer 2012American Legion Baseball2006-2010Tournament of StarsSummer 2009

Technical Skills:

Experience with Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Publisher, and Excel (including creating formulas)

Experience with Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Snapchat

Education:

UNC Greensboro 2011-2015

Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies

Indiana University 2010-2011

Additional Information:

Very experienced with foreign travel

Live broadcasting for American Legion Tournament 2010